A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal, Series Z FA335
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Personal Papers, 1878-1960, 1974; 2; 35 Document Box(es)
  - Book Collections - "Catalog of the Library", n.d. (Box 16, Folder 152)
    One copy is annotated.
  - Briefcase of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Tiffany and Company (Box 17, Folder 153)
    Black leather, gold stamping.
    General note
    Fragile.
  - Carriage Catalogs, 1954, 1956, 1958, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 154)
  - Drivers' License, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 155)
  - Diaries, 1884-1887 (Box 18, Folder 156)
  - Diary, 1888 (Box 18, Folder 157)
  - Diary, 1896 (Box 18, Folder 158)
  - Diary, 1901 (Box 18, Folder 159)
  - Diary, 1946-1947, 1950-1957, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 160)
  - Diplomas - Brown University (Box 19, Folder 161)
    1914 M.A., 1937 LL.D.
  - Invitations
    Lists of invitations received. Acceptance correspondence kept in some cases. 1916-1918 Canadian Club, Ottawa. 1919-1923, Industrial Relations. 1929, Edison Memorial. 1940 J.M. Speers Dinner. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    - Invitations, 1916-1917 (Box 20, Folder 162)
    - Invitations, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 163)
    - Invitations, 1919-1921 (Box 20, Folder 164)
    - Invitations, 1922-1923 (Box 20, Folder 165)
    - Invitations, 1924-1927 (Box 20, Folder 166)
    - Invitations, 1928-1931 (Box 20, Folder 167)
    - Invitations, 1932-1939 (Box 20, Folder 168)
    - Invitations, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 169)
    - Invitations, 1941-1948 (Box 20, Folder 170)
    - Invitations, 1949-1953 (Box 20, Folder 171)
    - Invitations, 1954-1960 (Box 20, Folder 172)
  - Invitations - Light's Golden Jubilee (50th Anniversary of Edison's Incandescent Lamp), 1929-1936 (Box 20, Folder 173)
  - Letters of Appreciation, 1916-1960, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 174)
    Spontaneous tributes to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s spirit, good works, example. Thanks for Williamsburg, Riverside Church, Phelps Castle. Some comments on worthy sons. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Letters of Appreciation, 1916-1960, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 175)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, 1901 (Box 21, Folder 176)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (A), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 177)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (B), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 178)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (C), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 179)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (D), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 180)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (E), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 181)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (F), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 182)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (G-H), 1951 (Box 21, Folder 183)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (I-J), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 184)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (K-L), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 185)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (McA-Ma), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 186)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (Me-N), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 187)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (O-P), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 188)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (Q-R), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 189)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (S), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 190)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (T-V), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 191)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller (W), 1951 (Box 22, Folder 192)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Marriage to Martha Baird Rockefeller - Unanswered, 1951 (Box 022A, Folder 0192A)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Victory (A-C), 1958 (Box 022A, Folder 193)
    Alphabetical arrangement. Letters commenting on NAR's victory in New York State election, 1958. Rev. Hanson prayers at inauguration. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Letters of Congratulations - Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Victory (D-H), 1958 (Box 022A, Folder 194)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Victory (I-N), 1958 (Box 022A, Folder 195)
  - Letters of Congratulations - Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Victory (O-W), 1958 (Box 022A, Folder 196)
  - Not Used (Box 022A, Folder 197)
  - Letters of Congratulation - Wedding Anniversary, 1952 (Box 022A, Folder 198)
    Three letters of best wishes. Laurance S. Rockefeller, Robert W. Gumbel, and Dr. J. McCracken.
  - Marriage Publicity, 1951 (Box 022A, Folder 199)
    Publicity on marriage to Martha Baird. Newspaper, radio, T.V. coverage. Biography of Martha B. Rockefeller, description of wedding. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Memberships, Clubs, Affiliations, 1914, 1936-1953 (Box 022A, Folder 200)
  - Memorabilia - Autograph Book, 1883 (Box 23, Folder 201)
  - Memorabilia - Bible Verses, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 202)
  - Memorabilia - Box, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 203)
  - Memorabilia - Brown University Marshal's Ribbons - Commencement, 1897, 1937 (Box 24, Folder 204)
  - Memorabilia - Calling Cards of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller (Box 25, Folder 205)
  - Memorabilia - Granite Specimen, Antarctica, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 206)
  - Memorabilia - Groom's Cake, 1901 (Box 25, Folder 207)
  - Memorabilia - House Keys, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 208)
  - Memorabilia - Ink Wiper, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 209)
  - Memorabilia - Journal of Quotations, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 210)
  - Memorabilia - Necklace Designs, 1925 (Box 26, Folder 211)
  - Memorabilia - Paperweights, 1935, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 212)
    Very Heavy.
  - Memorabilia - Pendants, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 213)
  - Memorabilia - Playing Cards, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 214)
  - Memorabilia - Pressed Flowers from England, 1889 (Box 26, Folder 215)
  - Memorabilia - Wallet, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 216)
  - Memorabilia - Memorials to Friends Written by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1922-1941 (Box 27, Folder 217)
  - Memorabilia - Framed Miniature of John D. Rockefeller, Sr., circa 1938 (Box 27, Folder 218)
  - Memorabilia - Miscellaneous Papers, 1883-1906, 1922 (Box 27, Folder 219)
  - Memorabilia - Photograph Albums, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 220)
    Silver, hinged and engraved, containing family portraits.
  - Photographs - Furnishings - 26 Broadway Office, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 221)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Book I, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 222)
    Color photographs. Arranged by disposition 1958. Black and white photographs of items given or traded away.
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Book II, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 223)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Book III, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 224)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Book IV, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 225)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Inventory, 1925, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 226)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Exchanges - Parish-Watson, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 227)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Gifts to Brooklyn Museum, January 1945 (Box 29, Folder 228)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Gifts to Colonial Williamsburg, January 1936 (Box 29, Folder 229)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Gifts to Metropolitan Museum, April 1945 (Box 29, Folder 230)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Metropolitan Museum Porcelains, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 231)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Gifts to Rhode Island School of Design, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 232)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Porcelains Given Away or Traded, 1958 (Box 29, Folder 233)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Trades to Duveen, 1925, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 234)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Trades to Parish-Watson, 1914-1925, 1930-1931 (Box 30, Folder 235)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Trades to Parish-Watson, 1935-1936 (Box 30, Folder 236)
  - Photographs - Porcelain Collection - Trades to C. T. Loo, February 1935 (Box 30, Folder 237)
  - Photographs - Pottery Purchases, 1914, 1916, 1920, 1922 (Box 30, Folder 238)
  - Photographs - Pottery Purchases, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 239)
  - Photographs - Pottery Purchases - Duplicate Photographs, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 240)
  - Printed Material - "Dew Drops", 1879 (Box 30, Folder 241)
    Inscribed to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. by his mother.
  - Not Used (Box 30, Folder 242)
  - Printed Material - "The Longfellow Birthday Book", 1881 (Box 30, Folder 243)
  - Printed Material - "Selections from the Thoughts of Marcus Aurelius", 1884 (Box 30, Folder 244)
  - Printed Material - "The Third Reader," Appleton Company, 1878 (Box 30, Folder 245)
  - Publicity Clippings, 1917, 1924-1939 (Box 31, Folder 246)
    Clippings about John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Pictured with carriage and team. Colorado Plan. Prohibition gifts. Brotherhood. Wartime Red Cross. Philanthropy. Child raising. "Rockefeller Challenges Capital" (1923). John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on New Deal taxation. Articles on children. Ickes attack on the rich, 1937. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity Clippings, 1940-1961 (Box 31, Folder 247)
  - Publicity Clippings - "America's Sixty Families" Article - "The New Republic," November 17, 1937, 1937-1939 (Box 31, Folder 248)
  - Reference File (A), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 249)
    Miscellaneous collection of sayings, sermons, extracts from letters, humorous and serious stories, observations and discussions of a variety of topics. They range from the duties of parents and children, Christianity, Sex, Sin, Courage and Ambition to Joy of Living, Stewardship and Patriotism. In them are many of the thoughts which John D. Rockefeller, Jr. later incorporated into his own beliefs. Although it would probably be impossible to trace the genesis of any single idea in his thinking from these notes, they tell much about his thoughts.
  - Reference File (B), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 250)
  - Reference File (C), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 251)
  - Reference File (D), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 252)
  - Reference File - Death, 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 253)
  - Reference File - Definitions, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 254)
  - Reference File (E-F), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 255)
  - Reference File - Family Writings, 1919, 1923, 1941, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 256)
  - Reference File (G-H), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 257)
  - Reference File - "Helpful Poems and Verses Sent Me at the Time of Abby's Going" (Box 32, Folder 258)
  - Reference File (I), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 259)
  - Reference File (K-L), 1886-1948 (Box 32, Folder 260)
  - Reference File (M), 1886-1948 (Box 33, Folder 261)
  - Reference File - "Miscellaneous Helpful Thoughts", n.d. (Box 33, Folder 262)
  - Reference File (N-O), 1886-1948 (Box 33, Folder 263)
  - Reference File (P), 1886-1948 (Box 33, Folder 264)
  - Reference File - Poems, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 265)
  - Reference File - Prayers, 1941, 1948, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 266)
  - Reference File (R), 1886-1948 (Box 33, Folder 267)
  - Reference File - Religion and Sermons, 1942-1946, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 268)
  - Reference File - Religion and Sermons, 1942-1946, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 269)
  - Reference File (S), 1886-1948 (Box 33, Folder 270)
  - Reference File (T-Y), 1886-1948 (Box 33, Folder 271)
  - Reference Clippings, 1912-1923 (Box 34, Folder 272)
  - Reference Clippings - Labor Strikes, Living Costs, 1945-1947 (Box 34, Folder 273)
  - Reference Clippings - Liberty, Freedom, Democracy, 1938-1945, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 274)
  - Reference Clippings - Osmansky-Gans Swindle, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 275)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s name forged on checks used in swindle. Forger and partners caught. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. appeared in court to testify. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Reference Clippings - Peace, 1943-1946, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 276)
  - Reference Clippings - Religious Thought of Military Leaders, 1942, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 277)
  - Reference Clippings - World War II - Letters to, from, about Soldiers, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 278)
  - Reference Clippings - World War II - Miscellaneous, 1945-1946 (Box 34, Folder 279)
  - Reference Clippings - World War II Politics, 1939-1943 (Box 34, Folder 280)
  - School Papers - General - Essay, ca. 1886 (Box 35, Folder 281)
  - School Papers - General - Expense and Driving Records, 1888-1890 (Box 35, Folder 282)
  - School Papers - General - Measurements (Dr. Savage's Physical Development Institute), 1890-1892 (Box 35, Folder 283)
  - School Papers - General - "Notes Made by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. ... as to His Early School Connections", 1951 (Box 35, Folder 284)
  - School Papers - General - Prayer Cards, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 285)
  - School Papers - General - Yale University Entrance Examination, 1891 (Box 35, Folder 286)
  - School Papers - New York School of Languages - Compositions, 1885, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 287)
  - School Papers - New York School of Languages - French Verb Conjugations, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 288)
  - School Papers - New York School of Languages - Penmanship Exercises, 1885 (Box 35, Folder 289)
  - School Papers - New York School of Languages - Report Cards, 1883-1885 (Box 35, Folder 290)
  - School Papers - Douglas School - Lesson Reports, 1885-1886 (Box 35, Folder 291)
  - School Papers - Cutler School - Compositions, 1887 (Box 35, Folder 292)
  - School Papers - Cutler School - Honor Rolls, 1885-1889 (Box 35, Folder 293)
  - School Papers - Cutler School - "School Diary", 1886-1889 (Box 35, Folder 294)
  - School Papers - Forest Hill, Cleveland - Compositions, 1889 (Box 35, Folder 295)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Address, 1890 (Box 35, Folder 296)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Art Portfolio, 1890-1891 (Box 35, Folder 297)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Class Schedules, 1890-1891 (Box 35, Folder 298)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Debating Exercises, 1889-1890, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 299)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Essays, 1889-1891 (Box 35, Folder 300)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Geometry Exercises, 1889-1891 (Box 35, Folder 301)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Greek Grammar, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 302)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Latin Notebooks, 1889-1890 (Box 36, Folder 303)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Notebooks, Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 304)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Rhetoric Notes, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 305)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Roman History Notes, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 306)
  - School Papers - The Browning School - Spelling Blanks, ca. 1893 (Box 36, Folder 307)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Admission and Registration Materials, 1893-1897 (Box 36, Folder 308)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Alumni Publications, 1897-1898, 1938, 1946, 1956, 1957, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 309)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Alumni Publications, 1897-1898, 1938, 1946, 1956, 1957, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 310)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Commencement Correspondence, 1897, 1915 (Box 37, Folder 311)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Dormitory Room Plan, 1893 (Box 37, Folder 312)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Essays, 1894-1895, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 313)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Examinations, 1893-1897 (Box 37, Folder 314)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Football (Printed Material), 1896 (Box 37, Folder 315)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Grade Reports, 1893-1897 (Box 37, Folder 316)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Invitations, 1893-1897 (Box 37, Folder 317)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - American History, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 318)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Art History, 1896 (Box 37, Folder 319)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Classical Archaeology, 1893 (Box 37, Folder 320)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - English Poetry, 1894-1895 (Box 37, Folder 321)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Ethics, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 322)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Greek, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 323)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - History and Astronomy, 1895-1896 (Box 37, Folder 324)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Latin Literature, Roman History, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 325)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Political Economy, 1897 (Box 38, Folder 326)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Lecture Notes - Psychology, 1896-1897 (Box 38, Folder 327)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Notes on Books Read, 1895-1896 (Box 38, Folder 328)
  - School Papers - Brown University - Petition, 1896 (Box 38, Folder 329)
  - Travel Records, General - List of Trips Taken, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 330)
  - Travel Records, General - Passports, 1896-1946 (Box 39, Folder 331)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - European Trip - Diaries, 1887 (Box 39, Folder 332)
    With John D. Rockefeller and family. Ships diary - SS Aller.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - European Trip - Diary, 1889 (Box 39, Folder 333)
    Ships diary - SS City of Paris.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - England and Wales Trip - Diary, 1895 (Box 39, Folder 334)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. traveled with Willard S. Richardson.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - European Trips - Diaries, 1896, 1897 (Box 39, Folder 335)
    Europe, 1896. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Alta Rockefeller Prentice met Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and Lucy Aldrich. Holland to Switzerland, 1897. Traveled with Willard S. Richardson.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - Cuba Trip - Diary, [1900?] (Box 39, Folder 336)
    Cuban Trip, 1900. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. traveled with the Aldrichs.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - European Trips - Diaries, 1900, 1901, 1905 (Box 39, Folder 337)
    European Trip, 1900 - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, and family. England, 1901 - Everett Colby and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Cannes, 1905 - John D. Rockefeller and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - Panama Trip - Diary and Loose Material, 1913 (Box 39, Folder 338)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - Oriental Trip - Diary, 1921 (Box 39, Folder 339)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England, 1923 June-August
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s first trip in 17 years. Took whole family with him except Winthrop and David. Letters to Winthrop and David Rockefeller from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller describing trip.
    France - Visited Versailles. Purchases from Lacarde.
    England - Souvenir newspapers and pamphlets. Visits to various homes and estates. Visited Parliament. Heard carillon concert at Taylor Co. Denyn played. This trip made to let children see points of historic and artistic interest.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence, December 1922-August 1923 (Box 39, Folder 340)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence (B-W), 1923 (Box 39, Folder 341)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence - Equitable Trust Company, 1923-1924 (Box 40, Folder 342)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence - Hotels, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 343)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1923-1924 (Box 40, Folder 344)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence - Powell, F. E. - Anglo-American Oil Company, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 345)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence - Pritchard, Edith, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 346)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Correspondence - Warwick Castle, 1923-1925 (Box 40, Folder 347)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Diary, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 348)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Itineraries, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 349)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and England - Printed Material, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 350)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy, 1925 October-December
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Robert W. Gumbel and wife accompanied. Trip taken for rest.
    France - Letters to and from French. About appointments, meetings, appeals for aid. Purchase of Byzantium tapestry. Offers of art objects. Gifts to wounded French veterans.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Correspondence, October-December 1925 (Box 40, Folder 351)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Correspondence, October-December 1925 (Box 40, Folder 352)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Correspondence, 1926-1932 (Box 40, Folder 353)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Correspondence - Equitable Trust Company, 1925-1926 (Box 40, Folder 354)
      Equitable Trust - Transfer of funds.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Correspondence - Hotel and Chauffeur Arrangements, 1925 (Box 40, Folder 355)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1925-1926 (Box 40, Folder 356)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France and Italy - Diary, 1925 (Box 40, Folder 357)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - France, 1927 June-August
    Took Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and five boys. Made primarily to visit the Cathedrals of France with Riverside Church in mind.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France - Correspondence and Passenger Lists, 1927 (Box 41, Folder 358)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France - Correspondence - Auto Hire, 1925-1927 (Box 41, Folder 359)
      H. Varnusson managed chauffers for European driving, rented cars to family.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France - Correspondence - Customs and Purchases, 1927 (Box 41, Folder 360)
      Statements, Customs, Purchases - Descriptions of purchases.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France - Diary, 1927 (Box 41, Folder 361)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - France - Itineraries, 1927 (Box 41, Folder 362)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip, 1929 January-March
    Breasted's help planning for trip. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Dr. Breasted, and Robert W. Gumbel made month-long journey down Nile. Friends and acquaintances in Cairo. Side trip to Jerusalem. Return home. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, J. H. Breasted.
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Calling Cards Received, 1929 (Box 41, Folder 363)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - General, 1928-1930 (Box 41, Folder 364)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - General, 1928-1930 (Box 41, Folder 365)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - General, 1928-1930 (Box 41, Folder 366)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - General, 1928-1930 (Box 41, Folder 367)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - General, 1928-1930 (Box 41, Folder 368)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Equitable Trust Company, 1928-1929 (Box 41, Folder 369)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Haick Travel Bureau, 1929-1934 (Box 41, Folder 370)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Hotel and Ship Accommodations, 1928 (Box 41, Folder 371)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Hotel and Ship Accommodations, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 372)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Passports, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 373)